# **Marcus Wiberg**

Berlin, Berlin, Germany



in linkedin.com/in/marcuswiberg



hi@marcuswiberg.com

# Summary

I'm a Swedish/American serial entrepreneur with a passion for solving exciting problems with unique and intuitive experiences where the customer is in the front seat.

I have built platforms used by millions of people, supported cancer patients with therapy through medical products, and raised millions in funding for startups.

# Experience



### Founder | Product

**MW Ventures** 

Sep 2010 - Present (9 years 11 months +)

Supporting startups with product development and strategy.

#### - Senior Product Owner

LivingPackets

Oct 2019 - 2019 (3 months)

Sustainable and convenient packaging for the e-commerce industry.

Demo: https://vimeo.com/375857637

#I led product management related efforts and introduced software development processes.

# CES 2020 Innovation Awards Honoree and Green Alley Award 2019.

# Platforms: iOS, Android, Web, and Embedded software.

#### mika Head of Product

Mika

Jun 2019 - 2019 (7 months)

Driven by the vision to improve the well-being and therapy outcomes of cancer patients. In cooperation with the Charité, the University Hospital Leipzig and the NCT Heidelberg (National Center for Tumor Diseases) Funded by https://ananda.vc/

#I led engineering, research, content, and product management efforts.

# Partnerships and collaborations with pharmaceuticals and insurance companies.

# Platforms: iOS, Android, and Web.



#### Founder | Product

SnapSound - Powered by SoundCloud

Dec 2018 - 2019 (1 year 1 month)

Snapsound is a music video editor with 180 million tracks of music. Powered by SoundCloud.

#I led engineering, research, QA, and distribution in 34 countries.

# Built a community of young people in South America to accelerate growth and user feedback.

#I designed the UX & UI and assets for 34 different languages for AppStore Connect.

# Gold Winner of international business award Stevie Awards 2019.

# 4.9 stars from 189 people on Apple AppStore (globally)

# Shutdown by SoundCloud.

#### **Solution** Head of Product

#### Matmatch

Mar 2018 - 2019 (1 year 10 months)

Matmatch helps you find, evaluate, and source the best materials for your industrial projects.

Trusted by more than 2.5 million engineers and designers.

Demo: https://vimeo.com/246770278

#I led the product department and product management related efforts.

# Conducted workshops about lean startups and product strategy.

# Main tools: Kibana (ElasticSearch), Google Analytics, Gitlab, Invision, Sketch, and Slack.

# Interview about my work at Matmatch https://matmatch.com/blog/how-matmatch-is-continuously-enhanced/

# Senior Product Manager

#### Matmatch

Oct 2017 - Mar 2018 (6 months)

# Handover of product from Boston Consulting Group Digital Ventures (BCGDV)

# Product owner of internal and external tools.

# Founder | Product

#### Switchplace Sverige AB

Sep 2015 - May 2017 (1 year 9 months)

Real estate platform established to tackle the growing demand for apartment swapping in Sweden.

Demo: https://vimeo.com/153559746

#I co-founded the company with designers, developers, and a marketing agency.

# Built a community with thousands of registered apartments in Sweden.

# Platforms: iOS, Android, and Web.

# S Founder | CEO

#### Socialmist AB

Sep 2010 - Jan 2017 (6 years 5 months)

Socialmist was a social networking platform with music from SoundCloud.

Demo: https://vimeo.com/283530006

#I raised ~2.4M USD in funding by Swedish and American investors.

# Reached Top 10 on the App Store (Category: Social networks)

# Built a strong community of young people to accelerate growth and user feedback.

# Signed partnership with VS model Kelly Gale & launch events with Kygo https://vimeo.com/157730641 https://vimeo.com/153559591

# Managed 25 full-time employees (mostly engineers, designers, and product managers)

# Platforms: iOS, Android, and Web.

### **Education**

# \*\* Academy for Academic Excellence

High School Diploma, English Language and Literature

# Sjölins Gymnasium

High School Diploma, Business/Managerial Economics

# | Kunskapsgymnasiet (Gothenburg, Sweden)

High School Diploma, Communication and Media Studies

### **Licenses & Certifications**

# **G** Google Analytics For Beginners - Google

Issued Aug 2018 - Expires Aug 2020

# G Advanced Google Analytics - Google

Issued Dec 2019 - Expires Dec 2021

# **Google Analytics for Power Users** - Google

Issued Dec 2018 - Expires Dec 2020

#### **Skills**

Entrepreneurship • Start-ups • Product Management • Agile Methodologies • Product Development • User Experience • Mobile Applications • Software Development • Business Strategy • Marketing Strategy